Rony Vargas

ronyvargasjr@gmail.com ❖ (347) 785-3767 ❖ Brooklyn, NY

Passionate and sharp with years of experience in engineering, technology, and design. Offered high-quality engineering solutions to the five boroughs of New York City. Evaluated the functionality, availability, and performance of large enterprise z/OS-based systems with a keen attention to detail and proficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ryan Consulting Engineers, P.C.

May 2024- Present

Sprinkler (Plumbing) Project Designer

Manhattan, NY

- Define the project's scope of work and design criteria to produce creative concepts that align with the client's goals and project requirements in compliance with NFPA13, NYC Building Code, NYC Plumbing Code, etc.
- Develop detailed designs, schedules, engineering notes, and specifications for fire protection & plumbing projects.
- Prepare documentation for each stage of the project for both clients and team members. Build an extensive list to manage plumbing/fire sprinkler projects, including mechanical and electrical, to maintain project workflow.
- Research local codes, regulations, and standards for mechanical, electrical, and plumbing/fire sprinkler systems.
- Perform Hydraulic Calculations for fire protection systems and Load Calculations for mechanical systems.

IBM March 2022 – October 2023

Software Test Specialist

Poughkeepsie, NY

- Responsible for weekly monitoring of z/OS consisting of managing IBM z/OS workloads, conducting system
 health checks, and ensuring that z/OS-based systems function correctly, and meet performance/availability
 requirements with up to 99.9999% uptime for clients.
- Validated the procedures of the Quick Start Guide for IBM z/OS Virtual Server Instances so that clients can clearly understand documentation and successfully run their existing workloads and applications with no issues.
- Assessed upgrade workflow procedures on zOSMF by identifying issues before impacting clients/organizations.
- Actively participated in daily scrums, weekly sprint planning estimations, and defect management meetings.

Sideris Kefalas Engineers, P.C.

October 2013 - March 2022

Fire Sprinkler Designer / Engineer's Assistant

Queens, NY

- Designed fire sprinkler systems for office, retail, residential, and multipurpose buildings in compliance with NFPA13 and New York City Building Code (NYC BC).
- Performed on-site surveys of fire sprinkler systems to ensure design and installation accuracy. This includes the
 incoming water service, the backflow preventer device (BFP), and distances between sprinkler heads.
- Created engineer reports from survey findings to communicate areas of improvement or discrepancy.
- Coordinated with fellow engineers, architects, and contractors to satisfy clients' needs and ensure that all trade drawings don't conflict with one another.
- Submitted forms and drawings to the Department of Environmental Protection for information and approval.

EDUCATION

Queensborough Community College - AAS, Mechanical Engineering Technology Queens, NY May 2016

 Studies: Computer Aided Design, Computer Controlled Manufacturing, Thermodynamics, Thermo-Fluids, Manufacturing Processes, Metallurgy and Materials, Applied Mechanics, etc.

Transfotech Academy - Manual/ Automation Testing

Remote January 2022

• Studies: Software Development Life Cycle, Bug Life Cycle, Software Test Life Cycle, QA processes, Different Software Testing Types, Data Validation and Verification using SQL queries, Xcode simulator, etc.

SKILLS

Software: Jira, MySQL, TestRail, Postman API, AutoCAD, Fusion 360, Elite Fire, Google Workspace

Code: C#, Python, SQL, JCL, IBM Assembler